We know that AI coding tools produce
generic looking UIs, but it gets even
worse when you're building an entire app
with multiple screens and interconnected
flows. Every page looks like it was
designed in isolation because it was. No
shared system, no cohesion, just a
hodgepodge of disconnected outputs. So,
you reprompt, you rebuild, but each
iteration drifts further and further
from any coherent vision. What's missing
is a design process. A way to make
deliberate decisions before your coding
agent wires up the back end so that you
can hand off perfectly tuned designs.
Not mock-ups, but productionready
components for a cohesive front end
across your entire app. This is design
OS. It's the missing step between your
product idea and your codebase. I built
it to solve the front-end design problem
in my own work. It's a guided process
where you and AI plan your product,
design your screens, and then export
productionready components that any
coding agent can implement. So, the days
of creating mock-ups by hand only to see
them get lost in translation, that's
over. Now, we can design our actual
front end with an AI first design
process. Design OS is free and open
source. You can download it, use it, and
see all the docs by going to
buildermethods.com/designos.
In this video, I'll show you how it
works. By the way, I'm Brian Castle. I'm
the creator of AgentOS, a popular
framework for spec driven development
with AI and now design OS. I also run
builder methods where pro members get
support, training, and community for
building software with AI. All right,
now let's dive in. Design OS organizes
your process into three phases. Phase
one is product planning. You establish
your foundation, your product's vision,
your data model, and your global design
system. Phase two is where you design
each section of your product. You shape
the requirements, then generate some
sample data, and then design the actual
screens. And phase three exports your
product's design in a package that's
ready for implementation. This lets you
hand off finished front-end components
and also gives you ready-made prompts to
instruct your coding agent on exactly
how to use your designs and build your
app. You'll interact with Design OS
through a series of commands. These are
structured conversations where AI guides
you through each decision. No staring at
a blank page, no guesswork, just a
methodical planning and design process.
Now, design OS is its own standalone
project. It's separate from your app's
codebase. It's built on React, VIT, Shad
CN, and Tailwind CSS. Now, I recommend
you use Cloud Code to run the commands
that are included in Design OS. But if
you prefer a different tool like Cursor
or Codeex or Gemini or any of the
others, it's easy enough to reference
and run those same commands. All right,
now let's start by getting Design OS
installed. I'll start by going to the
docs and I can go down to setup and go
to installation. And you can clone the
GitHub repository by just copying this
command right here. Now, you'll want to
change my product design with the name
of your project. Now my project today is
going to be called salesy but I'm going
to actually add design here because
salesy alone will be the name of the app
but this project is separate. This is
just for design OS. So I'm going to call
it salesy design and then we're going to
cd into salesy design and we'll just run
that all in one command. Okay. So, I've
just pulled down all of the files for
Design OS, uh, including the Claude
commands, and those are inside of this
Design OS folder. And we have the Claude
code skill called front-end design. And
the rest of this is the React and Vit
app that will power Design OS. And then
just, you know, following along with the
installation instructions, we'll remove
the original remote. And then I want to
npm install. And then let's start it up.
MPM rundev. That's on localhost 3000.
Okay, here we go. Design OS is up and
running on my system. Uh, ready to start
a new project. Now, the way that Design
OS is laid out across the top is our
overall process starting from the
product vision. And then we're going to
move into the data model, the design
tokens, and the design shell. Uh, then
we'll get into designing each individual
section. And then finally, we will
export our package. The first step in
any design OS project is defining the
vision for your product. This is where
you establish the core identity of what
you're building. What problem does it
solve? What are the key features that
make this possible? You don't need to
have all the answers figured out ahead
of time. The product vision command
starts that conversation. You share your
rough ideas and AI will ask you
clarifying questions and together you
shape everything into a clear product
overview. And looking at design OS, the
first step in the product definition
page is to run the product vision
command. So I'm going to just run that
in cloud code /vision.
And you'll know that that's the command
because it's preceded by design OS. So
I'm just going to run that. So first
thing is it asks me to define my product
vision. It says tell me about the
product you're building. Any notes,
ideas, rough thoughts? What problem are
you trying to solve? Who's it for? Don't
worry about structure yet. just share
what's on your mind. Now, I've prepared
a prompt to use here. And this is, you
know, typically my starting point for a
new product. I have a couple of ideas
and and rough structure in my mind. It
looks something like this. Now, in this
case, I'll be building an app that I'll
be calling salesy. And it says that
it'll let you easily create simple
sharable sales pages to request payment
for something, a product, a service, and
optionally personalize these pages to a
client. Now, each sales page should use
a clean branded layout separate from the
main app's shell because that will be
client-f facing. So, that's all that I'm
putting into my initial prompt. And
sometimes I'll put even less than this.
You know, as you can see, there's
probably some holes and and a lot of
open questions, but this is a good start
for my new product. So, I'm going to
paste that into Claude, and we'll start
from there. All right. So, now Claude is
going to start to ask me some clarifying
questions. First, it's asking me about
the target user. And I think that I'll
actually select two of those. Right.
It's asking me what metrics matter most
for tracking sales page performance. And
you know, here's an example of something
where I sort of want to course correct
it and and add my own notes to this. So
instead, I'm going to go to the fourth
option and just type something in. I'm
going to say I'm going to say I just
want to track the number of sales pages
that I've sent. All right. Then I'll
submit those answers. Okay. So, it has
drafted up a description and a couple of
problems and solutions and a couple of
key features based on its understanding
of what we're building here. So, you
know, I would sort of like read through
this and if I have any uh corrections or
notes that I want to add, I can add
those in. But, you know, for now, I'm
just going to say this is good. So, now
it's actually showing our product
overview for this app that we're
building. Here's the description. Here's
the list of problems and solutions that
we're setting out to solve with this
product. And then we have a list of key
features. All right. So now our product
is starting to take shape. And so now
based on this, our next step as I go
down in the process here is to run
product roadmap. And what this is going
to do is it's actually going to break
down our product concept into a couple
of key sections that are sort of
buildable and self-contained screens
that we're going to need in our app. And
so that's going to start to form a road
map for our entire design process. So
let's run product road map. All right.
So just like that, it has come up with a
list of about four sections. So we've
got sales pages. That's where we would
uh like create the sales pages. We've
got a clients area. Uh we've got a main
dashboard, of course, and then the
public page. Yeah, I think that's a
that's a really good start. Of course,
we'll have like settings pages and maybe
some other pages tied into these, but
these are like the main sections of the
app. And you might even think of these
as links in our main navigation. So,
I've got a couple of options here, of
course, but I'm just going to say looks
good. All right. So, with that, now we
have those four sections listed here
under sections. And now I can of course
move on into the next phase. Next up is
your data model. Now, if you've never
done any back-end development, this
might sound intimidating, but here's the
thing. This step is conceptual. It's not
technical. You're not writing database
schemas. You're just defining the nouns
of the system. The main things that
users will create, view, and manage,
like users or projects or invoices or
tasks, whatever makes sense for your
product. AI will help you think through
what entities you need and how they
relate to each other. So whether you're
a technical founder who wants
architectural control or you're a
non-technical builder with a clear
product vision, this step helps you
establish a strong foundation that will
guide everything that follows. Okay, so
we're on the data model page and the
only step to do here is run the data
model command. So let's run that slash
data model. Notice how easy it is to go
step by step through this guided
process. All right. And just like that,
it says, "Looking at your product, here
are the entities that I'm seeing that we
would need a sales page, client, and
payment." Now, for the purpose of this
design process, I would say that is that
is just fine. And now, of course, when
we get into the final codebase, we're
going to have all sorts of other data
models like maybe users and accounts and
other stuff, but you know, for the
purpose of designing this new app, let's
just focus on these main entities. So,
I'm going to say good to go. All right.
So, it documented that data model into
this simple, easy to read. It just makes
sense, right? I'm looking at these
entities with, you know, short
descriptions and then relationships. how
a sales page belongs to a client and how
a client has many sales pages. Payment
belongs to a sales page. So, of course,
if you're experienced with back-end
development and data modeling, you'll
understand how these associations might
work in a codebase. But even if you're
not technical, you can just read this
and it's understandable. We're looking
at the nouns of our product. Now, before
we can design individual screens, we
need to establish our global design
system. This includes two things. design
tokens and your application shell.
Design tokens are your visual identity,
your color palette, your typography
choices. These decisions will cascade
through every screen you design,
ensuring consistency across your entire
product. And your application shell is
the persistent navigation and layout
that wraps all your sections. So, your
sidebar layout or your topnav or your
minimal header, whatever pattern fits
your product. Getting these right before
you design individual sections means
everything you build will automatically
feel cohesive and intentional. All
right, moving on into the design system.
So, this page has two steps. We're going
to start by running design tokens. So,
let's run that. And this is going to
help me establish our brand colors and
the fonts that we're going to be using
in our design system. So, it makes a
couple of suggestions. It's actually
pulling these color names from the
Tailwind CSS colors library. And it's
going to be using Google fonts. So,
which color vibe fits salesy best? And
it's even recommending uh this combo,
indigo, emerald, and slate. So, yeah,
that sounds good to me. All right. So,
which typography style do I prefer? Now,
I know that inter is, you know, kind of
overused, of course, but I think it
actually does fit pretty well here. It's
clean, professional, highly readable.
Cool. All right. So, it has put in our
design tokens. Of course, we can uh take
a look at those right here. The nice
thing here about establishing these now
is that in all of the design sections,
we're always going to be using these
exact colors rather than designing each,
you know, screen in isolation where AI
might start to tweak and use different
colors for different pages. We don't
want that. We want consistency. All
right, let's go ahead and actually start
designing the shell. So, I'll just run
the design shell command. Now, of
course, application shells can come in
all different types of configurations
and shapes and sizes. So, it's going to
ask us, you know, what kind of layout
are we working with here? Do we want a
sidebar navigation or a top navigation
or some kind of minimal header? I think
in this case, we will go with a side
navigation. And which section or which
view should be the default view when the
app actually loads? We'll we'll say the
dashboard should be that. All right. So,
it's working on designing that shell
component. Now, while that's cooking, I
just want to show you where all of these
pages, all this content is actually
being stored. There is no actual
database built into Design OS. But all
of this content is being stored in basic
markdown files right here in the product
folder. So, we've already finished the
the design system. The data model is
just a markdown page. And you know, that
first product overview is right here.
And the product road map is right here.
So, you know, I can go into these simple
text files and make any edits that I
want along the way. All right, that's
all set. So, let's take a look at it.
So, I'm going to scroll down here and we
have the application shell with a little
description of it. And then here is the
link to actually view our shell design.
And so, the now I almost forgot. Every
time we design a new screen, including
the application shell, it's best to go
into your server and restart it by
running mpm rundev. so that you know we
get all the new CSS assets and
everything all refreshed. Just restart
the server. And here we go. Our
application shell is looking pretty
good. We've got the sidebar layout here.
And this is our viewer for previewing
all of the designs that we're going to
be creating in Design OS. So this outer
part is just design OS and the inner
part is the actual design. So this is a
slidable, you know, resizable container.
We can do that or we can use these handy
buttons to go from desktop to tablet to
mobile sized. And so this actually did a
pretty good job of setting up a sidebar
navigation with a little navigation
menu. We've got a settings thing down
here that looks pretty good. And the
other thing is Design OS has dark mode
built into it. So we've got a little
toggle right here and I can click that
and it's going to put the whole thing
including the design itself into dark
mode. And you know design OS along with
the help of the front-end design skill
in claude you know instructed the agent
to actually make sure that we are
designing every screen to be responsive
and every screen to have dark mode and
light mode capabilities. So it looks
like it did a pretty good job of of
doing that. If you want to actually
break out of this screen and look at it,
you know, without the container, you can
just click full screen. And now we're
looking at the actual design completely,
you know, in the browser. All right, so
I can go back here into the design OS
interface and we're ready to move on
into designing each section. Now we get
to the fun part, designing individual
sections. For each section in your road
map, you'll follow three steps. First,
you'll shape the section. This is where
you define what it does, the user flows,
the UI requirements, what's in scope,
and what's not. The shape section
command guides you through a
conversation to nail down a simple spec.
Then you'll generate sample data. This
will be used to populate your designs
with realistic content. Not lurim Ipsum,
but actual names, dates, varied
statuses, edge cases, and finally you're
ready to design the screen. This creates
actual React components, fully
responsive light and dark mode using
your design tokens. And by the way,
Design OS includes the Claude front-end
design skill developed by the Claude
team specifically to create distinctive
professional-grade interfaces that avoid
generic AI aesthetics. It guides bold,
creative choices in typography, color,
layout, and motion. Okay, so we're here
in the sections section of Design OS
where again we have all of the the main
sections that we're going to be
designing here. Starting with the sales
pages section. Now, each of these uh has
its own, you know, trackable process.
So, I'm going to go into the sales pages
section first. And again, we're going to
start by shaping up a simple spec for
the design of this section, followed by
generating some sample data. And then
we'll actually design the screens for
the sales pages section. And then, sort
of as an optional final step, we can
actually snap screenshots of the
designs. All right, let's start with
shaping up the sections spec. So, I'll
run shape section. All right. So, first
it just starts off by asking me if I
have any notes or direction or, you
know, design specs or anything that I
want to drop in here. So, if you have
any of those notes, now's the time to
drop them in. Of course, I could always,
you know, go through the conversation
and and add more as we go. But, one
thing that I do want to specify here is
that the sales pages section is actually
going to need to consist of a few
different pages. So I'll say the sales
pages section will need three distinct
screens to design. First is the index of
all sales pages. Next is the edit view
where we edit a sales page. And finally
the clientfacing
and actually I realized that we won't
actually need to design the public
facing sales page since we already have
that planned as its own section. So
we'll get to that a little bit later.
Uh, but for this section, I'm just going
to be designing the index of sales pages
and the editable sales page. It's funny,
it caught my mistake. So, I had said
three screens. I actually meant two. I'm
going to sort of clarify that for Claude
here. Oops, I meant two screens. Just
index and edit. All right. So, what
information should be shown? And I like
how it suggests like pretty sensible
ideas here. So, I can just, you know,
pick one or I can course correct and
type something. Yeah, I'm going to say
all of the above. All right. Now, for
the edit screen, it's yeah, I want this
third option. And yeah, so for creating
a new sales page, I think in this case,
we can keep it pretty simple. We'll just
do a new button to a little modal popup.
That works for me. All right. What UI
pattern should be used here? Let's just
go with list rows. And I love how easy
it is to just answer questions and just,
you know, select an option. Occasionally
I need to actually type in, you know,
some extra notes and whatnot, but this
whole guided process and clarifying
questions makes designing an app and
getting all the details right really
pretty easy. All right, so it's running
back everything that it just gathered
here. And again, this is another
opportunity for me to, you know, add
anything or course correct anything, but
I'm just going to say good. Okay, so now
here on the sections list, you can see
the spec step has been checked. And then
if I go in here now, we have this is a
very simple spec and that's by design.
We want to keep it very simple here.
Just an overview, a list of some user
flows and a list of UI requirements.
Now, we're going to move on into
generating some sample data. And this is
sort of like some secret sauce in this
AI first design process. by generating
some sample data which will be in in
JSON format that's going to really help
us dial in our actual design so that AI
will design our interface including
exactly what we need in that interface
without all the extra bells and whistles
that AI tends to throw into our designs.
That's why we want to generate some
actually realistic sample data. So for
that I'm going to, you know, run the
sample data command. And right after I
run that, it actually generates a
preview of what will go into my sample
data. So even if you're not technical,
you could sort of just read through this
and you can sort of make sense of it.
Right? Again, we're just talking about
the entities or the nouns, if you will,
that make up the data, the content, and
the the modeling underneath our
application. Now, don't worry about this
being absolutely accurate. Uh this is
not set in stone. And this is really
just a part of our design process to
dial in our front-end designs. Once we
get into our final code base later on,
that's when, you know, we're going to be
much more accurate and really, you know,
fine-tune our database modeling and our
columns and everything. This is for the
purpose of just sample data, right? So,
I responded to that with that's good.
And off of that, Claude is going to
actually generate some some sample data
in JSON format. All right, so that's all
set and uh we can review our sample data
right here. Here's the data model. Here
is how they connect. In this case, it's
just a list of sales pages. And then we
can look at that JSON. Again, this might
look like a bunch of code to you, but if
you start to read through these lines,
these are actual realistic sounding
pieces of content that would go into a
list of sales pages that will populate
our index view. So, I'm going to
collapse that. And now we can finally
get on to actually designing the first
screen, which is going to be the the
index view. So, let's go ahead and run
design screen. And I'm going to add a
bit of detail here. Since our sales
pages section is going to have two
separate screens to design, I'm just
going to say first design the index
screen. And you can see here that Claude
is reading the front-end design skill
and then creating the index screen. So
that's that's really good. That's sort
of like baking in a little bit extra
design muscle into Claude when it goes
about creating this screen. Okay, so
that is all set. Shut down the server
and run it again. MPM rundev. So here we
go. Under screen designs, uh, this sales
page index is ready for me to see. I'm
going to click that. And here we go. I'm
looking at the index view for the sales
pages. It it followed all of the details
that we had actually discussed during
the planning phase to, you know, create
a new sales page. This here is a real
front-end design view. You'll also
notice that it is placed within our
actual shell. The the shell has not
changed. We're not designing these in
isolation. So, we've kept the shell.
We've kept our design tokens, our
colors, our fonts. It's all consistent.
Uh, let's check it out in in some mobile
configurations and let's check out dark
mode. Yeah, looking good. All right, so
I'm going to go back into viewing this
section for sales pages. Now, not all
sections are going to have multiple
screens to be designed, but this one
happens to have another screen that I'm
going to need to have designed. So, for
that reason, I'm actually going to rerun
the same command again. We're going to
run that design screen and I'm going to
say now design the edit view for a sales
page in the sales pages section. So you
can see how it's reading and drawing on
our colors and the front-end design
skill once again some you know types and
and the sample uh data set. So, it's
it's using all that all that information
that we've established methodically
building up to this point where we're
actually ready to assemble not only a
functional but an accurate user
interface design. Okay, so that is all
set. Now, once again, I'm going to
restart the server, end it, and then run
it again. And let's refresh this page.
And now we have two screen designs
listed here. Let's go ahead and view
that edit sales page. So, here we go.
Once again, we are inside of our shell.
It's all consistent in that regard. And
we're viewing a single sales page. It's
edit view. Here's the setting for what
happens after a person clicks. Up here,
we've got this like copy link. That's
kind of cool. The UI components are in
place. Let's see how we're doing as we
drop down into mobile view. And that's,
you know, that's all looking good. And
dark mode as well. Good stuff. All
right. I'm going to go back to this
section. Now, as I scroll down, we've
got one more step, and this is to snap
some screenshots of the two designs that
I've just created. I would say that this
step is actually optional. Again, we
have already designed and built the
functional screens. So, we don't
necessarily need to have screenshots to
reference, but especially if you're
working with a team or with clients or
other stakeholders, it might be good to
to, you know, generate some some
screenshots of this stuff. Now, of
course, I could just use any
screenshotting tool to to make these
screenshots myself, but Design OS has
screenshotting capability built in. And
for that, we use the the Playwright MCP.
So, let's let's see how that works. I'm
going to run the screenshot design
command. Going to go ahead and run that.
And first, Design OS is going to
actually check to see if I already have
the Playright MCP installed. And
actually it found that on my system
currently I don't actually have it
installed. So it actually gave me the
command that I need to run to install
the playwright MCP and activate it for
cloud code. So I'm just going to copy
that. Now this is not a command that you
would run in cloud code itself. I
actually need to exit cloud code and you
know just in the terminal that's where
you want to actually run that command.
Run that. I'm going to start Claude
again and I can do slashmcp
to see which MCPS I have installed on my
system. And currently I just have the
one playright. It says that it's
connected. So So that's good to go. All
right. So now I'm going to actually just
press up to to get back that previous
prompt that I that I gave to to Claude
here. Um and once again I'm I'm going to
be calling that design OS screenshot
design command. And I'm telling it,
let's screenshot both the index and edit
views for the sales page section. Okay.
So here it's actually using Playwright
to launch its own browser instance. I'm
not controlling this and it is just, you
know, viewing both of those screens. I
can see in two separate tabs. It opened
them in full screen mode. So it's not
going to screenshot like the design OS
container. It's just going to, you know,
screenshot the actual design. Okay. So,
it just closed down the browser and now
it's going to take those screenshots and
it's placing them in my product folder.
And so, first we can, you know, view
those screenshots right here. So, now
our whole section for sales pages is
complete. We have the two screenshots
right here, those screenshots. But just
to show you this whole time while we're
building out the product and then
building out each individual sections,
all the content that we're creating with
Design OS is being stored in here. So
the first section that we've done here
is sales pages. Inside that we've got
our sample data JSON. We've got that,
you know, basic spec that we've created
early on. Got some some types and we
have those two screenshots right here.
So here is the edit view and here is the
index view. Awesome. And if I go back
and view all the sections now, I can
just repeat that same process for
designing the pages for the client
section, the dashboard, and that public
sales page. So, I'm going to pause the
video here off camera. I'm going to go
ahead and, you know, rerun that process
and finish out all these designs. So,
I'll be back in a minute. Okay, I'm
back. It's about 15 20 minutes later and
I've gone through and I finished the
designs for all four of these sections.
As you can see, they're all checked off
here. So, if I go into the client
section, we have the spec, the sample
data, and two screen designs for that.
So, here is the client's list, which I
think looks great. We've got some
metrics across the top. Pretty nice. And
then we've got the um the client's
detail. So, I can view and edit a uh a
single client here. Then, we've got the
dashboard view. And this was just a
single view. I've got the screenshot for
it down there, but here is that
dashboard. We've got some metrics, some
uh some some filtering capability here,
and a list of recent activity. And this
is all looking great. Again, I've got,
you know, dark mode working for all
these designs. I think it did a really
great job on this public sales page.
Again, this one is client facing. So, it
actually asked me and then I confirmed
that this one will not be shown inside
of the main application shell because
this is what clients will see, right?
So, here's the sample data. And then
here is that public view. As you can
see, it's much cleaner. We have the, you
know, the branding for whatever the
user's company is. And then we've got
sort of like a sales letter and a a call
to action button. Little subtle motion
animation on that. This looks really
great. You know, this is the work of
Claude Opus 4.5 with the with the
front-end design skill built in that you
know, you'll have that available to you
throughout all of Design OS. All right,
so we've got all the sections ready to
go. And once all your sections are
designed, it's time to export. The
export product command generates a
complete handoff package. Everything
your coding agent needs to implement
your product. This includes your product
overview, your data model, your design
system, and all your designed
components, plus pre-written prompts to
kick off implementation and test writing
specs so that your agent can use a
testdriven development approach when
building out each section. All of it
organized, documented, and ready to drop
into your codebase. All right, so we're
in the final phase of Design OS, and
that's the export phase. And as we can
see here, we are now ready for export.
It tells me what is going to be included
in our export package and uh you know it
gives me sort of uh details about all of
that here. Uh but let's go ahead and run
this export product command. So I'm back
in cloud. I'll just run export product.
This is going to take a few minutes to
run because it's actually going to grab
everything inside of my product folder.
and it's going to do a little bit of
like reconfiguration of the design
components, sort of the code uh
underneath the hood to make sure that
it's all highly portable and ready to
drop into my codebase. It's also going
to prepare some pre-written prompts
that'll make it really easy for me to
hand off to my coding agent. But I'm
going to let this cook and and prepare
my uh my export. All right. So that
export process is all set and uh I can
see it here now on the export page. We
have the link to download uh the zip
file which is product plan.zip
and we can actually just see the
contents of that um right here in uh the
design OS codebase. So um earlier as we
were building out all of our screens and
all of our designs, all of that was
happening in the product folder. But now
we have a folder called product plan and
this is like our export package. So, you
know, it lists out everything that went
into this. We've got a couple of prompts
that we can use uh in the
implementation. I'll show you that next.
You know, we have each of the individual
sections. And if we open up components,
you know, these are actual, you know,
React components that are ready to be
dropped into our codebase. We've also
got our product overview, which is uh,
you know, sort of just the overview of
what this product is all about. Go into
this export page. Scroll down and now we
have these simple step-by-step
instructions for how we can implement it
in our codebase. Now, when it comes to
implementing your designs in your
codebase, you've got two options. Option
one, and this is generally my
recommended option, is incremental
implementation. You work through each
section one at a time. foundation first,
then the shell, then each feature
section in order. Each milestone has its
own instruction file and prompt. You
implement, review, test, and then move
on to the next one. Option two is
oneshot implementation, and this can
work for simpler apps or when you just
want to build everything in one session.
The oneshot prompt gives your coding
agent everything all at once. It'll ask
clarifying questions about O and data
modeling and then plan and implement the
whole thing. And either way, you're
handing off complete productionready UI
components. Your coding agents job is to
build the backend, wire up the data
layer, and integrate, not recreate
designs from screenshots. Okay, so here
on the final export page in Design OS,
our export package is all ready. I could
just click this to download the product
plan zip to my machine, you know, or I
can get all of those files right here.
They're they're in the codebase for
Design OS as well. So, let me show you
how I would get started with
implementing our designs in an actual
codebase for this application. So, I've
downloaded the the zip file that's on my
desktop right here, and then I've
unzipped it right here. So, and I'm
going to bring that over into this other
project. So, this would be my actual
codebase for the application that would
become salesy. In my case, I'm using
Ruby on Rails with React. I'm using
Inertia with that. So of course you can
use anything for your back end whether
it's Laravel or Nex.js or Python or
anything else. Um as long as you are
using React on the front end then you
can easily import these design
components. So here is that you know new
project for the actual codebase and here
on the right is the folder for this
codebase and then here on the left is my
product plan folder on my desktop. So
I'm simply going to take that product
plan folder and drop it right into my
codebase just like that. And so now it's
here. So let's take a look at what we
have here. Of course, we have like the
data model, the design system, fonts,
tailwind colors, tokens, but what you'll
actually want to use are one of these
two prompts. And remember, if we look at
the export page and you scroll down,
you'll have these very simple
instructions how to use the export.
Option A, incremental, and that's
generally what I recommend. And option B
would be to, you know, build the whole
thing in one shot, which could work for
simpler applications. So, I'm going to
show you how I would get started with
both. So, if we were to take the
incremental approach, you'll want to use
the section prompt. And you'll use this
repeatedly for each of the sections. If
I'm using the oneshot approach, then
I'll use the oneshot prompt. So, you
would use one or the other. You probably
wouldn't want to use both. Now let's
also open up the instructions folder.
And here we have oneshot instructions
and we have a folder called incremental.
Again you would use one or the other. So
in the incremental case this one has a
numbered set of you know incremental
milestones that we'll be building one by
one. So for each one of these starting
with a foundation and then and then
designing the application shell and then
going through those four sections that
we've designed. For each of those, we'll
we'll be using our section prompt to to
get the agent started on that. And I'll
and I'll show you how I would do that in
just a second. But just to round this
out, down here, we have the actual
sections. And each of these contain the
actual React components that our coding
agent will take and integrate into this
codebase. So, you really don't need to
touch this stuff too much because they
are all prepped and ready for your agent
to, you know, integrate and wire up into
your codebase. But it's all here in the
product plan. So let's actually get the
process started. Again, we're going to
start with the incremental approach. And
I'm going to open up Claude. Now, I
definitely recommend you start with plan
mode. And the prompts sort of assume
that you are starting in plan mode. So
to toggle into plan mode in Cloud Code,
you do shift tab until you see it says
plan mode on. Okay. So, that's really
important because uh that will enable
the agent to not only analyze all of the
instructions and all the files that
we're going to throw at it, but also
analyze your current codebase and start
to ask you some implementation questions
to really dial in that that plan for
wiring it all up and getting all those
integration details right as they relate
to your codebase and your tech stack.
Now, in the case of taking the
incremental approach, we will open up
the prompts and I'm going to open up
that section prompt right here. Now,
before we actually drop that into
Claude, I'm going to drop it into this
text file uh just so that I can define
these three variables at the top. Since
this is a prompt that we're going to be
using repeatedly for each section, we
just need to tweak the values here
uh for each of the different milestones
that we're going to be running. So we're
going to start by doing the foundation
and that's foundation and I can see that
if I open up the instructions under
incremental we're starting with
foundation and then the number is 01. So
this is sort of like the name of the
section and this is the exact name that
we see in this file name and then this
is the number of the milestone. So what
this does is basically just instructs
the agent that whenever you see section
name in these instructions, we want that
to be this. Whenever you see NN, we want
that to be 01. And that will help it
identify the specific files that we will
be pointing the agent to go read and
analyze and bring into its context.
Defining these up here just makes it
easy so that you don't have to like find
all the little instances in this in this
prompt to get those going. So each time
we we run this, I'll update these three
values. Okay. So that is all set. I mean
one more thing, this is optional, but if
you have any other additional technical
notes or directions that you want to
give to your agent up front, you can
just, you know, add them into the prompt
here. But of course, the the agent is
going to ask you clarifying questions
because we are in plan mode. All right,
so let's go ahead and get that prompt
into Claude. And I just pasted that in.
I can see that here. And since I'm just
demonstrating how to get started with
this, I'm going to sort of leave it
there. But I do want to point out a few
more things that we will be giving to
Claude. Again, if we look at the section
prompt, you can see that for each
section, we're providing a readme file.
And let's look at one of these sections
as an example. If I look at the client
section, we've got this readme. And this
gives Claude all the context about
what's happening in the client section,
what the user flows are, what our design
decisions were um and a little bit of of
instruction on how to wire it up. We're
also giving it that sample data. This is
more for like reference purposes. We're
giving it those React components which
are in the components folder. These are
actual, you know, React components. And
then this is interesting. We're giving
it a test.md.
And so if we look at that, these are
instructions to the coding agent on how
to write tests for this section of the
application. Now, design OS doesn't
necessarily know what your tech stack
is, which framework you might be using
for your test suite, but this gives the
agent just general instructions on what
the key user flows are, like what the
success path is and what the what the
failure path would be. You know, all of
the critical flows that we should have
test coverage for, especially since we
want the agent to take a test driven
development approach. So each section
comes with this pre-written tests
instructions file which will inform your
agent on how to get started on writing
the the critical tests and planning the
implementation. So all of that stuff is
getting referenced from the prompt that
we're giving to the agent here. But to
keep it absolutely simple, all you
actually need to do is take the prompt,
update those variables, and then drop
the prompt right into cloud code in plan
mode. Let it analyze everything. Let it
ask you clarifying questions and then
let it let it run and do the
implementation. And then of course after
that, you'll want to test its work,
review it. You might need to add in
additional specs and tasks for the agent
to to wire up some backend business
logic that might not have been covered
in all of the specific designs that
we've already created. That's totally
normal, especially when you're taking
this incremental approach. Um, but
that's the process, right? So, so we
would start by doing you know some of
the foundation work and then as we move
from the foundation we would take the
the next step in our incremental process
here which would be the shell. So in
that case you would just you know rerun
that whole process again you would you
change this to shell shell and that's O2
and then you know copy and paste into
plan mode have it analyze it ask your
questions let it run build it test it
review it and then you move on to the
next one which in this case would be
setting up the dashboard so for that we
would just go dashboard dashboard and
that is 03 then once again you just do
it again so that's the incremental
approach you know you you
one through six. Now, let me show you
the other approach, which is the oneshot
approach. This is better for simpler
applications. It's pretty similar except
we'll just be doing it all in one shot.
So, I'll just delete this for now and
we'll go back to our prompts folder. And
in this case, we are not going to be
using the section prompt anymore.
Instead, we're going to be using the
oneshot prompt. And so, this is the one
that we will want to give to Claude Code
or whichever coding agent you're using.
I'll copy that. Now, since this is just
a one-time use prompt, we don't need to
actually change any variables. Uh, since
we're not, you know, using it repeatedly
for different milestones. It's just one
big one big build here. So, in this
case, I would just, you know, copy and
paste and I'll delete that from earlier.
And then just paste that in. Now, this
one is going to point Claude to your
oneshot instructions, which are here.
And, and this is sort of similar to the
incremental instructions, except it
covers everything. It covers all the
sections from the shell to the clients
to the dashboard to the sales pages uh
in this case all of it. So once again,
you know, start that in plan mode, have
cloud code ask you questions, dial in
the the details for especially for the
backend business logic, let it run. And
in one shot mode, it'll be running for
longer since it'll be it'll have a lot
more to build in one shot. Um but you
know, go ahead and and let it run and
test its work and and there you go. you
can build an entire app in one shot. So,
that's how I would get started with
taking those finished front-end designs,
bringing them into the codebase and and
having Claude plan and then implement
the the integration of the front end and
wiring up the back end and your business
logic. So, that's design OS, the missing
step between your product idea and your
codebase. Go to
buildermethods.com/designos
to download it, use it, and access all
the docs for free. And if you want
official support, training, and
community as you use Design OS for
yourself or with your team, that's
available in my Builder Methods Pro
membership. You'll get access to me for
questions, a community of builders using
these tools, plus all my workshops and
training on AI first development. Thanks
for watching. Now go build something